I've got my code editor open inside that small project,
コードエディタでその小さなプロジェクトを開いています。
and I'm going to start up the development server with a NPM run
そして、NPMランコマンドで開発サーバーを起動します。
dev. And when I run that, I'm going to be able to
devです。それを実行すると、ブラウザの
navigate to a local host 3000 inside my browser
ローカルホスト3000にアクセスして
and see the application running. So here it is right here. We
アプリケーションが実行されているのを確認できます。これはここにあります。
are going to use Claude to do a little bit of work on this project.
このプロジェクトでClaudeを使って作業を行います。
But first, there's something really critical I want you to understand around
しかし、まずClaudeの使用に関して、本当に重要なことを理解していただきたいことがあります。
using Claude. Specifically, I want you to walk away
具体的には、コンテキスト管理をしっかりと理解して
from this course with a strong understanding of context management.
このコースを終えていただきたいのです。
You see, inside of your typical project, there might be dozens or
皆さんの一般的なプロジェクトでは、数十、あるいは
hundreds of files, each with a tremendous amount
数百ものファイルがあり、それぞれに膨大な量の
of information. Whenever we ask Claude a question
情報が含まれています。Claudeに質問したり
or give it a task, there is some ideal amount of
タスクを与えたりする際には、Claudeが必要とする理想的な量の
information that Claude needs. Just enough
情報があります。質問に答えるため、またはタスクを完了するために
to help to understand how to answer your question or complete your task.
役立つ十分な情報です。
As soon as we start adding in additional information that's
関連性のない追加情報を加え始めると、
not relevant, Claude's effectiveness will start
Claudeの有効性は低下し始めます。ですから、
to decrease. So it is really important for us to
Claudeをプロジェクト内の関連ファイルや
help guide Claude towards relevant files or
ドキュメントへと誘導することが非常に重要です。
documentation inside of our project. Claude code can
Claudeのコードは、手取り足取りなくても
certainly work without any handholding, but you'll get the best
確かに動作しますが、少しガイダンスを提供することで
results if you provide just a little bit of guidance.
最高の成果が得られます。
So for the remainder of this video, I'm going to give you a bunch of different tips
このビデオの残りの部分では、Claudeに可能な限り最高のコンテキストを与えるための
on how to give Claude the best context possible. To
さまざまなヒントをたくさん紹介します。まず、
get started, inside my editor, I've opened up my terminal, and
エディタ内でターミナルを開きました。
I'm going to start Claude Code up by running the Claude
そしてClaude Codeを起動するために、Claudeコマンドを実行します。
command. Whenever you run Claude Code
Claude Codeを実行する際、
in a project for the first time, I highly recommend running
初めてプロジェクトで実行する場合は、スラッシュinitコマンドを実行することを強くお勧めします。
the slash init command. This gets
これにより、Claudeはコードベース全体を深く調べます。
Claude to take a deep look at your entire code base. It'll
プロジェクトの目的、全体的なアーキテクチャ、
figure out the purpose of the project, the general architecture,
関連コマンド、重要なファイルなどを特定します。
relevant commands, critical files, and so on. After
この検索の後、その結果をClaude.mdというファイルに要約して保存します。
this search, it'll summarize its findings and place them
Claudeがこのファイルを作成しようとすると、許可を求められます。
into a file called Claude.md.
Enterキーを押して承認するか、
When Claude tries to create this file, it will ask for permission.
すべてのファイル書き込み要求に毎回許可を与えるのを避けたい場合は、
You can either hit Enter to accept, or if you don't
ShiftキーとTabキーを押すこともできます。これにより、
want to have to grant permission to every file write request,
Claude Codeがプロジェクト内で自由にファイルを書き込めるようになります。
you can also press Shift Tab, which will allow
生成されたClaude.mdファイルを開いて、
Claude Code to freely write files in your project.
その内容を確認することをお勧めします。先ほども述べたように、
I would encourage you to open up the Claude MD file that was generated
このファイルの内容は、Claudeに行うすべてのリクエストに含まれます。
and take a look at its contents. As I mentioned, the
このファイルには、実質的に2つの異なる目的があります。
contents of this file are included in every request we make off
まず、Claudeがコードベースをよりよく理解するのに役立ち、
the Claude. This file really has two different purposes.
関連するコードをより迅速に見つけられるようにします。そして第二に、
First, it helps Claude better understand your codebase so
Claudeに一般的なガイダンスを与える場所として機能します。
it can find relevant code more quickly. And second, it
ご存知のとおり、Claude Codeが利用するClaude.mdファイルは複数あります。
serves as a location where you can give Claude some general
プロジェクトレベル、ローカルレベル、マシンレベルがあります。
guidance. Just so you know, there are multiple
プロジェクトレベルは、スラッシュinitコマンドを実行して生成したものです。
Claude MD files that Claude Code will make use of. There
通常、このファイルをGitのようなソース管理にコミットします。
is a project level, a local level, and a machine
このファイルを他のエンジニアと共有し、
level. The project level is what we just generated
プロジェクト固有の指示をClaudeに渡します。オプションで、
by running the slash init command. We are generally
Claude.local.mdファイルを作成することもできます。
going to commit this file to source control, like Git. We're
このファイルはコミットされず、通常は他のエンジニアと共有されません。
going to share this file with other engineers and just have some project
このファイルには、個人的な指示を記述できます。
specific directions that we want to hand off to Claude. Optionally,
Claudeにあなたのためだけにフォローしてほしいものです。最後に、
we can also create a Claude local MD file.
マシン全体にグローバルなClaude.mdファイルを持つことができます。
This file is not going to be committed and you're generally not going
このファイルには、ローカルで実行するすべてのプロジェクトに適用される
to share with any other engineers. Inside this file,
指示が含まれます。さて、
you might put in some personal instructions that you want
Claudeに特別な、あるいはカスタムの指示を与えることを何度も言っています。
Claude to follow just for you. Finally,
ですから、例をお見せしましょう。例えば、
you can have a global Claude MD file on your machine.
Claudeがコードを書く際にコメントを使いすぎる場合を想像してみましょう。
This file will contain instructions or be applied to all
Claude.mdファイルを更新することで、これを対処できます。
projects that you run locally. Now, I
ファイルを直接編集することもできますし、少し
keep on mentioning giving Claude special or custom instructions.
ショートカットとして、Claude Code内で
So let me show you an example of that. Let's imagine that
ポンド記号を入力することができます。これにより、
Claude is using comments way too often in the code that it writes.
メモリモードに入ります。これにより、Claude.mdファイルのいずれかを
We can address this by updating our Claude MD file.
インテリジェントに編集できます。
We can either manually modify the file or a little
「コメントをあまり書かないでください」のようなリクエストを入力できます。
bit of a shortcut is inside of Claude Code we
次に、この指示をプロジェクトの
could put in a pound sign. This puts us in
Claude.mdファイルに追加したいと指定します。
memory mode. This allows us to edit one of our
Claudeはインテリジェントにこの指示をマージします。
Claude MD files intelligently. So we can put
その後、ファイルを開いて検索すると、
in a request like, don't write comments so often. I'll
実際に新しい指示が追加されていることがわかります。
then specify that I want to add this instruction to the project
Claude.mdファイルを作成したので、特定のコンテキストを
Claude MD file, and Claude is then going to merge
会話に引き込む方法をより深く理解していただきたいと思います。
this instruction into that file intelligently. If
このプロジェクトの認証システムがどのように機能するかを
I then open the file up and do a search, I'll see that in
よりよく理解したいと想像してみましょう。
fact, yes, it did add in that new instruction.
単純にClaudeにそれについて説明するように依頼することもできます。その場合、
Now that we've created our Claude MD file, I want to give you a
コードベース全体を検索し、認証システムに関連するファイルを見つけます。
better understanding of how to pull in specific context
それは確かに機能しますが、
into a conversation. Let's imagine that we want to better
ある程度の時間がかかります。あるいは、
understand how the authentication system in this project works.
認証システムに関連するファイルがすでにわかっている場合は、
We could just ask Claude to tell us about it, in which case, we would
アット記号を使ってそれらを参照できます。
search over our codebase and find files relevant
ファイルを指定すると、それが自動的に
to the authentication system. That would definitely work, but
Claudeへのリクエストに含まれます。これは素晴らしいテクニックで、
it would just take some amount of time. Alternatively,
Claudeを特定の方向に導くことができます。
if we already know some files that are relevant for
同じ構文を使用して、Claude.md内のファイルを指定することもできます。
the authentication system, we could mention them using
その理由を示す例を挙げましょう。このプロジェクトの
the ATT character. When we mention a file,
Prismaフォルダ内に、schema.prismaというファイルがあります。
it will be automatically included inside of our request off to
このファイルには、このプロジェクト内で情報を保存するために使用される
Claude. This is an excellent technique for
SQLiteデータベース内に存在するすべての異なるテーブルとレコードタイプの
pointing Claude in a specific direction. You
完全な定義が含まれています。
can use the same syntax to also mention files
この情報はプロジェクトの多くの側面にとって非常に重要で関連性が高いため、
inside of Claude MD. Let me show you an example of
Claude.mdファイルにこのファイルを指定することを検討するかもしれません。
why that is really useful. inside of the Prisma
どのように行うかを示します。まず、
folder of this project, there's a file called schema.prisma.
ポンド記号を入力してメモリモードに入ります。次に、
This file contains a complete definition of all the different
スキーマファイルを指定し、具体的にはClaudeに、
tables and types of records that exist inside the SQLite
データベース内のデータの構造をよりよく理解する必要があるたびに、
database that is used to store information inside this project.
そのファイルを参照するように伝えます。
Because this information is so important and relevant
更新が完了したら、Claude.mdファイルを見て、
to so many aspects of this project, I might decide
メモが追加されたことを確認します。このようにファイルを指定すると、
to mention this file inside of my Claude MD
その内容は自動的にリクエストに含まれます。
file. Let me show you how I do that. First,
ですから、ユーザーがどのような属性を持っているか尋ねると、
I'll enter a pound to enter memory mode. I'll then
Claudeはスキーマファイルを読まずにすぐに答えることができます。